Mohankumar Markuli Chandrayigowda

Liverpool, United Kingdom +44 7833838626

mohankumar.mc@proton.me

in www.linkedin.com/in/mohankumar-mc

github.com/Mohankumar-MC

Summary

Graduate with a strong background in business and big data analytics who thinks strategically. Has experience using Python, SQL, Excel, and Tableau to improve business and give strategic insights. Proven skills in working as a team, paying attention to details, being flexible, working with people from different cultures, and carefully engaging stakeholders. Skilled at breaking down complicated ideas into insights that are easy to understand and use. I want to use a mix of technical skills, business sense, and strategic analysis to solve complex business problems in a fast-paced role.

Education

MSc in Business Analytics and Big Data (Merit)

2022 - 2023

University of Liverpool, United Kingdom

Modules: Data Mining and Machine Learning, Big Data Management, Digital Business Technology, Big Data Analytics for Business, Digital Strategy, Enterprise Systems using SAP, Project and Portfolio Management, and Sustainable Supply Chain Management.

Bachelor of Computer Science and Engineering (First-Class)

2016 - 2020

Visvesvaraya Technological University, India

Modules: Mathematics, Python, Web Development Technologies, Cloud Computing, Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning, Object Oriented Programming, Big Data, Database Management Systems, Computer Networks.

Skills

- Languages: Python, R, SQL, Java, JavaScript, HTML/CSS.
- Tools: Excel, PowerBI, Tableau, SAP HANA, YouTube Studio Analytics, Knime Analytics, IBM SPSS Statistics, Jupyter Notebook, GitHub, Google Cloud Platform, VS Code, PyCharm.
- Frameworks: Angular, Node.js, Flask, JUnit, WordPress, and Spark.
- Libraries: pandas, NumPy, matplotlib, seaborn.
- Soft Skills: Communication, Teamwork, Leadership, Project Management, Attention to Detail, Adaptability,
 Stakeholder Engagement, Summarising Complex Ideas, Cross-Cultural Engagement.

Academic Projects

SAP S/4HANA 1809 Global Bike

MSc, Business Analytics and Big Data

- New product cost estimation with itemized views and develop a discussion report accordingly.
- Performing end-to-end Material Management operations from creating, routing, cost estimation, and mark price updates to view price changes.
- Performing cost control assessments (primary and secondary services) of materials and comparison reports on both manual and system operations.
- Successfully performed all case studies of S/4HANA 1809 Global Bike on MM, CO-PC, and PP.

Skills - SAP S/4HANA, Reporting, Auditing, Financial Analysis.

Online Notice Board

B.E, Computer Science

- Collaborated with the admin team at the university and implemented various features such as add, delete, and view options that streamlined the process of updating information on the online notice board, resulting in a 40% decrease in manual work at the university.
- Improved the overall usability of the online notice board by integrating a responsive design that allowed users to access notifications and articles on different devices without any issues, resulting in a 20% increase in mobile traffic.

Skills - git, MySQL Databases, Visual Studio, PHP, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Software Development.

Advanced Traffic Management System using Google Cloud

B.E, Computer Science

- Developed and implemented an automated IR-sense-based solution to dynamically shift traffic signals (red/green) using Raspberry Pi microcontrollers, reducing wait times at one junction by 30%.
- Designed a cloud-based storage system for all sensor data that informs the traffic status and provides priority passage for ambulances, increasing emergency response time by 40%.

Skills - git, Google Cloud, Python, Sensor Identification and Integration, Project Management, Scrum.

Work Experience

University of Liverpool, United Kingdom

Jun 2023 - Sep 2023

Project: Ethical Issues of Using AI in Business Operations | PG Student Research Assistant

- Conducting a comprehensive systematic literature review on Al ethics debates, analysing over 50 academic articles and industry reports.
- Case study analysing the effect of innovative ERP systems on the business operations of Motor Oil Hellas.
- Identified and documented emerging ethical issues associated with the use of AI technologies, including privacy concerns and potential biases in decision-making processes.
- Developed a set of recommendations for companies to ensure ethical practices in their use of AI technologies based on analysis of publicly available cases.

Skills - Research, IBM SPSS, Data Analytics, Business Analytics, Project Management, Supply Chain Management.

Infosys Ltd., Bengaluru, India

Dec 2020 - Jul 2022

Project: Content Creator and Educator, Clients: Springboard and ETA | Al and ML Educator

- Trained hundreds of employees, senior members of the organization, and clients of Infosys Ltd. on methods and benefits of using Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning in business operations
- Continuously upskilling in new technologies related to Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Data Science
 through online courses and industry conferences. Implemented new learnings into ongoing projects resulting
 in a reduction of manual effort by 15% and increased accuracy by over 25%.
- Created data dashboards, graphs, and visualizations using Tableau, communicating insights to stakeholders, product owners, and senior teams.
- Led knowledge-sharing initiatives and crafted compelling case studies that led to beneficial outcomes, displaying adaptability and resilience.
- Helped maximum tech employees of a particular DC to upskill in 3 months making them aware of AI and ML inspiring them with new technologies directly impacting the long-term goal of Infosys Nio.

Skills - Python, EDA, ML, Project Management, Model Evaluation, Knime Analytics.

Project : Zoiee, Client: Multiple Event Services (Chatbot) | Systems Engineer

- Restart and allocate virtual servers at Infosys Ltd. AI chatbot named Zoiee for different client events.
- Handling multiple clients simultaneously and providing services.

Skills - Server Maintenance, Linux, Virtual Machines, Technical Support.

Project : GenQ, Client: Springboard | Systems Engineer Associate

- Implemented a responsive design for the complete user interface of a major project, resulting in increased user engagement by 40% and reduced bounce rates by 25%, which was featured in 'India AI 2021'.
- Collaborated with a team to structure and analyse business requirements, transforming them into functional specifications for developers and providing strategic solutions.

Skills - git, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Angular, TypeScript, JavaScript, Java, MongoDB, Agile Methodologies.

Achievements

- Al and ML Educator at Infosys Global Education Center (the world's largest corporate training centre).
- Business Communication level 5 certified.
- Infosys certified Executive program in Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning.